Nabil Farhan Mahmad Zulhasnan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

Kuala Lumpur, MALAYSIA

□ (+60) 11-1004-3129 | ■ nnabilfarhan@gmail.com | 🚳 www.nabilfarhan.com | 🖸 nabilfarhan | 🛅 nabil-farhan

"Don't be afraid to fail, be afraid not to try."

About Me

I love writing code. Software development has been my passion since I was young. I love technical challenges and am interested in all parts of development: analysis, architecture, coding, testing, deployment. Moreover, I have been obsessed with the idea of using software to solve practical problems. For me, Software engineering is a never-ending puzzle that I am passionately engaged in solving. I believe in the power of programming to transform and improve the lives of people around the world.

Skills_

Programming Javascript, Java, Python

Web Development Node, React, Redux, Angular, REST, StyledComponents, CSS, SQL, PHP, JQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB

Others Android, AWS, Git, Jira, UNIX, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

Languages English, Malay

Education

Multimedia University (MMU)

Cyberjaya, Malaysia

BSC (HONS) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE WITH SPECIALIZATION IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

March 2015 - June 2020

 Active in sports and represent MMU Football Team for IPT League, SIPMA (Sukan Institusi Pendidikan Malaysia) and SUKIPT (Sukan Institusi Pendidikan Tinggi)

Experience

Astro Malaysia Holdings

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Feb. 2020 - Jun.2020

- Responsible for developing bug-free application, creating front-end interfaces and maintenance using ReactJS for Astro SMS-Gateway team.
- Successfully generated back-end programming with server-side logic using NodeJS, SOAP and REST.
- Modified some code for lambda function using JAVA before rebuild and redeployed it to the AWS Lambda.
- Worked with MySQL and AWS RDS to insert/update customer addresses to the current production database.
- · Experience with JIRA and Confluence.
- Build and deploy some application to the AWS EC2 server using bitbucket/azure pipeline.

Footykids Malaysia Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

WEB DEVELOPER

Apr. 2019 - Present

- Developing a sports company website using PHP, Javascript, CSS, Bootstrap and MySQL.
- · Creating and maintaining databases using PHPMyAdmin as well as extracting and loading the test data on a regular basis for testing purposes.
- Websites were built locally on apache server then later migrated to live hosting using cpanel which is utilized to managed server and websites.
- · Install and managed some third party Javascript applications/widgets to integrate it into the website.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones and responsiveness of applications.

Projects

Codesharing 2019

GITHUB.COM/NABILFARHANN

• Collaborative Editor and Real-time Video Call with NodeJS

itsmyGram 2019

PHOTOLIB-27E7E.WEB.APP

• Photo sharing website (Instagram clone) with Angular and Google Firebase. *PWA Supported*

Vidhub 2019

VIDHUBS.HEROKUAPP.COM

· Video sharing website build with PHP and MySQL. The website implements Cloudinary as Cloud Storage.